Julius Reade

PR & Communications professional of four years, with a background in journalism, copywriting and broadcasting. Self-taught programmer of one and a half years with HTML/CSS, JavaScript and Python proficiency, as well as Adobe Creative Suite talents.

3 Saxton St Box Hill North, VIC 3129 0414388905 Julius.Reade@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Expotrade, Wheelers Hill - PR & Communications Executive

AUGUST 2015 - JUNE 2016

Global conference organiser with offices in Australia and Dubai. Creation and promotion of press releases and news-related information for Australian Head Office. Interstate travel for interview of ministers, prominent speakers and sponsors. Management of media inquiries and stakeholder relationships. Average event attendance: 250-300 private delegates and government officials.

Perspective Theory — *Managing Editor*

JANUARY 2015 - AUGUST 2015

https://www.perspectivetheory.com

Advice and self-help for those experiencing mental illness and depression. Promotion of content via marketing channels. Analysis and research of mental health issues and trends. More than 90,000 self-written words published.

Vision Australia Radio, Kooyong — *Producer & Announcer*

JANUARY 2012 - FEBRUARY 2015

Radio station dedicated to providing on-air programming and content for the blind. Producing and presenting a variety of different shows. Interviewing and recording talent. Segment production. Production of more than 100 episodes for Don't Hold Back.

EDUCATION

Monash University, Caulfield — Bachelor of Journalism

MARCH 2011 - OCTOBER 2014

Melbourne High School, South Yarra — VCE

JANUARY 2007 - SEPTEMBER 2010

SKILLS

Supporting strategic and tactical communications goals and plans.

Developing communication collateral with tight deadlines.

Proactively building strong, positive relationships with key stakeholders.

Strong Adobe Creative Suite skills in Photoshop, InDesign, Premiere Pro and Audition.

Video and audio production experience; commercial equipment available.

Experienced web developer with a strong HTML/CSS and JavaScript background.

Colemak keyboard layout, average 90 WPM.

AWARDS

The Zero Hedge Daily Round
Up online reviews:
http://podbay.fm/show/49421
9092/reviews

LANGUAGES

Minor in Chinese Language Studies at Monash University. Personal French study. .

PROJECTS

The Financial Reality — *Producer & Presenter*

SEPTEMBER 2011 - JULY 2013

https://www.youtube.com/user/thefinancialreality

YouTube Channel focused on political, financial and journalism news content. 28 videos produced. 2,000+ subscribers. 2,300+ video comments and likes. 225,500+ channel views. \$800 ad revenue.

The Zero Hedge Daily Round Up — *Producer & Presenter*

JANUARY 2012 - DECEMBER 2012

https://itunes.apple.com/au/podcast/the-zero-hedge-daily-round-up/id494 219092

Daily online news bulletin aimed at summarising prominent news events featured on financial website Zero Hedge. Six to seven minute podcast. Three hours to research, script, record, edit, upload and promote each morning. 138 episodes produced, receiving over 55,000 downloads. \$300 in fan donations.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Ozwashroom — Mulgrave, Marketing and Administration Assistant

JUNE 2015 - JULY 2015

Second largest supplier of washroom accessories within Australia. Creation of company graphics, email newsletters and product demonstrations. In-house SEO, SEM, Social Media and Google Adwords. Administration and Accounts handling.

McLeod Rail — Footscray, Digital Marketing Specialist

JUNE 2015

McLeod Rail is a specialist rail contractor and labor hire company. Casual employment. Implementation of digital marketing strategy. HTML newsletters, company CV and tender application review and design.

Prolearn — St Kilda, Education Consultant

FEBRUARY 2015 - APRIL 2015

Prolearn is a telemarketing company selling TAFE education to potential customers. Cold-calling, outbound sales. Basic administrative tasks.

Masters Home Improvement — Box Hill, *Customer Service Associate*

JANUARY 2013 - FEBRUARY 2015

Local hardware store. Retail and customer service. Invoicing and freight.